withlocals.com 2017-06-06

# Withlocals

**Privacy Policy Withlocals.com (last updated: July 25th, 2015)**

Your privacy is important to us. That’s why we have created the following Privacy Policy which applies at all times when using our website and / or any of our services. Any new features and/or services that are added to our current service at any point in the future shall also be subject to this Privacy Policy. Please familiarize yourself with it. To make this Privacy Policy easier to read we have provided additional everyday language summaries as a guide. 

## 1\. Applicability

#### When you visit our website or use our services you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy.

Withlocals B.V. (from here on referred to as "Withlocals", "we" or "us") provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding how we collect, use, manage, store, transfer and disclose the personal information that we receive from users of www.withlocals.com (the "Site"), our services and our application for mobile devices (the "Application") regardless of how you use or access them.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us via the Site and the Application. We reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect any changes to our services. We will do this by amending the Privacy Policy on the website. The changes will take effect automatically, as soon as they are posted on the site. In addition, we will notify all users by email if any material changes are made to the Privacy Policy.

In regards to this policy, the terms "using" and "processing" information include but are not limited to; the use of cookies, the collection, storing, transfer, evaluation, deletion, disclosure, management, handling, modifying and use of data.

## 2\. International transfer

#### We process your personal information in the European Union.

Your information may be transferred to – and maintained on – computers and servers that are located outside of your country of residence or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. 

Withlocals is based in The Netherlands. All information captured via the site will be transferred, held and processed in the European Union. By using the site and submitting your information you agree that your information can be transferred, stored and processed there.

## 3\. Information collection and use

#### We collect information to improve our services and/or website.

We collect information primarily to provide you with access to our services and tools and to provide you with relevant and personalized customer service. 

The information collected on our site may also be used to improve our site and the services, features and applications that we offer. 

## 4\. Personally Identifiable Information

#### We need some basic personal identifiable information in order to provide you with our services. If we ask more information, it is used to further enhance your experience of our services.

You can browse our site without having to submit personal information. If you register with us through the Site or Application you are no longer anonymous to us, however. 

When you register with us through the Site or Application and when you choose to serve as a Host or book as a Traveler, or when you wish to contact another visitor via our website, we will ask you for personal information that can identify you and be used to contact you ("Identity Information"). 

Identity Information includes, but is not limited to; your name, phone number, email address, home address, but does not include your credit card number or billing information. If you choose to provide us with personal information you consent to that information being transferred and stored on servers in the European Union. 

Some personal information is required in order to provide the service, for example: your name and email address. Other personal information is optional, including your date of birth. We reserve the right to require address confirmation if you are hosting events. 

Personal information is also used for the personalization of your Withlocals Account profile (without limitation, individual preferences or demographic information) ("Non-Identifying Information").

Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your personal information if it were combined with other identifiers in a way that enables you to be identified. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information. We may occasionally combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and use it to statistically evaluate the service and users, in order to provide better customer service and to improve the usability of the Site. 

We also use your personal information to contact you with occasional Withlocals newsletters and other information that may be of interest to you. You can decide at any time to opt out of these promotional and marketing communications by following the instructions for unsubscribing, which can be found on the Site. 

## 5\. Log data

#### The data your browser sends us when visiting our website is used to optimize our services.

When you visit the Site and / or use our Application, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ("Log Data"). 

This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, clickstream data, Internet Service Provider details, date/time stamp, language, the webpage you were visiting prior to visiting our site, the pages of our Site and Application that you visit, the length of time spent on each page and the frequency of visits, information that you search for on our site and other statistics. This information is used to help us refine and improve our Service to better suit the needs of visitors and Users. 

We do not treat Log Data as personal information or use it in association with other personal information, though we may aggregate, analyze and evaluate such information for the same purposes as stated above regarding other Non-Identifying information.

## 6\. Cookies

#### We use cookies for technical, analytical and commercial reasons.

As is common with most websites, we use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that is stored on the hard drive of your computer. You can delete cookies at any time.

Withlocals uses cookies and other technologies to remember personal information in order to make your experience more convenient and more personal, for example we save your login details. 

Cookies also help us better understand how you are interacting with the Site. We then use this information to improve Customer Service. 

You can opt out of cookies at any time by changing the settings on your browser. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to access or benefit from all the functionality of the Site and the Service.

We treat cookies as personal information.

## 7\. Account on our website

#### In order to make a reservation for an event or host an event, you’ll need to register with a Withlocals account and provide some personal information.

The Site, Application and Service can be used to facilitate the listing and booking of Events (eating events, tours and activities). Listings for such Events are made available via the Site, Application and Service by Hosts. Listings posted by Hosts, ratings and reviews of Hosts and Travelers, and the Profile Information (as defined below) of Hosts and Travelers, are visible to any Withlocals user, whether registered of not.

When you create a Withlocals Account you are agreeing to allow us to set up a Withlocals Account profile page on your behalf. Your Withlocals Account profile page will include your first name and last name. You can select the other items of personal information that you wish to be included in your Withlocals Account profile page – including, but not limited to, a profile picture, a personal profile and links to services you are offering, if applicable (together, your "Profile Information"). 

We will display your Profile Information in your Withlocals Account profile page publicly via the Site and Application, and, with your prior permission, on third party sites. Any information you choose to provide as part of your Profile Information will be publicly visible to all Withlocals Users, whether registered or anonymous, and consequently you must decide how much information you wish to share.

We encourage members to think carefully about what information they disclose in their public profile pages. You can review, revise or delete your Profile Information at any time.

## 8\. Information needed from Travelers and Hosts

#### When you book or host an event, we need to share some information to facilitate your experience and provide the best customer service.

If you post an Event, we may publish that Event publicly via the Site and Application and may enable third parties to publish your Event on their websites through the use of an HTML "widget". 

We may also display the general geographical location of your Event in the form of a map so that potential Travelers can see the general area and location of the Event.

If you make a booking via the Site, Application and Service, Withlocals will share the following information about you with the applicable Host: (i) your first and last name, and (ii) a link to your Withlocals Account profile page. 

This information will enable the Host to decide whether to confirm or reject the booking. When a Host confirms a booking we will share some of the Host’s Identify Information with the traveler via email, including, but not limited to; first and last name, phone number, the address where the Event takes place, and the Host’s email address, with the applicable Traveler selected by the Host. 

We will share some of the Traveler’s Identify Information with the Host, including, but not limited to; first and last name, phone number and email address, so that the Traveler and the Host may contact one another directly. Under no circumstance is a Traveler’s Billing Information ever shared with a Host.

## 9\. Sharing of information 

#### In order to improve our services, we will share information with third parties when needed.

From time to time, we may share aggregated information with third parties for strategic purposes. Any information shared in these contexts will not contain your personal information.

We may employ third party companies and individuals to help improve or facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Site and Application-related services, including but not limited to: maintenance services, fraud detection services, database management, web analytics, fraud detection services, monitoring and evaluation services.

These third parties may have access to your Personal information. If they do, your information is still protected by the terms of our Privacy Policy. This access is only granted to third parties so that they may perform these tasks on our behalf and they are obligated not to disclose your information or use it for any other purpose. 

We may also, on occasion, provide personal information to trusted entities and third parties for the purpose of providing you with information on goods or services we believe will be of interest to you.

You can, at any time, opt out of receiving such communications. 

## 10\. Compliance with laws

#### We will disclose information when required by law.

It may be necessary for Withlocals to disclose your personal information whether by law, litigation, legal process and / or by request from public or governmental authorities within or outside of your country of residence. 

We may also disclose your personal information if we determine that disclosure is necessary or appropriate for purposes of law enforcement, national security or to prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable.

We will disclose any information about you to our insurance services providers if we consider it necessary in order to protect the property and rights of Withlocals or a third party, and / or to protect the safety of the public or any person.

## 11\. Sharing and changing the information provided

#### You control the information stored by us and have the right to change and/or delete it.

Withlocals may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your personal information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

All Withlocals users may review, update, correct or delete the personal information in their personal profile by contacting us at info@withlocals.com or by editing the relevant part of their profile. 

If you would like us to cancel your Withlocals account, please contact us and we will attempt to accommodate your request if we do not have any legal obligation or a legitimate business reason to retain the information contained in your Withlocals Account. 

Please note that, if you cancel your Withlocals account, any reviews you have posted via the Site and Application will remain publicly viewable via the Site and Application. 

## 12\. Security

#### We take security very seriously.

Withlocals is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We take several precautions to safeguard against loss, misuse and theft of information. 

When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or Paypal address) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). This keeps your information safe while it is transferred over the internet. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. You are advised not to share sensitive data publicly. If you have any questions about security on our Site and Application, you can contact us.

In the event of any breach of security Withlocals will make any legally required disclosures concerning the breach and the confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" to you via email or via a posting on the Site and Application without unreasonable delay in as far as it is consistent with any legitimate needs of law enforcement and any measures required to determine the scope of the breach and to safeguard the integrity of data.

## 13\. Links to other websites

#### When we link to other websites, it’s just a link, nothing more.

Our Site and Application contains links to other websites. If you choose to visit one of these Sites by "clicking on" a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or by clicking on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party's website.

The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. 

If you choose to visit any of these third party websites you are governed by their Privacy Policies and Practices. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with these.

Withlocals Platform uses Google Maps/Earth mapping services, including Google Maps API(s) to pinpoint the general location of events that are offered as part of our Service. By using our Site you are agreeing to the use of Google Maps/Earth, which is subject to Google’s own terms of use and Privacy Policy. 

## 14\. Use of Cookies 

#### We make use of cookies to improve your user experience.

**How we use Cookies.**

Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites. We use cookies to help identify your device so we can tailor your user experience. Cookies will not be stored longer than one year. You can disable any cookies already stored on your device, but these may stop our website from functioning properly. 

The following is strictly necessary in the operation of our website.

#### Technical Cookies

**This Platform Will:**

  * Remember that you are logged in and that your session is secure. You need to be logged in to complete an order.

The following are not Strictly Necessary, but are required to provide you with the best user experience and also to tell us which pages you find most interesting (anonymously).

#### Functional Cookies

**This Platform Will:**

  * Cookies to make you use the platform more easy, like cookies remembering your selected currency or your search filters.

#### Analytics/performance Cookies

**This Platform Will:**

  * Measure the use of our website
  * Test the website UI
  * Use conversion pixels
  * Offer Live Chat Support
  * Track the errors on the pages you visit
  * Monitor performance of the website

#### Targeting Cookies

**This Platform Will:**

  * Serve you personalized ads based on your website behavior
  * Allow you to share pages with social networks
